Guide to the Larry McMurtry Papers
University of Houston Libraries
- McMurtry's Writings
  - Scripts
    - Somebody's Darling
      - Fifth draft: dropped pages (Box 19, Folder 22)
        Typescript pages
      - Fifth draft (Box 19, Folder 23)
      - Fifth draft: dropped pages (Box 19, Folder 24)
        Typescript pages, with corrections
      - Sixth draft (Box 19, Folder 25)
        Typescript draft (some photocopied), with corrections
      - Last revisions and possible cuts (Box 19, Folder 26)
        Photocopied typescript pages, with corrections; Typescript pages, with corrections
      - Diane Keaton and Jonathan Demme's notes (Box 19, Folder 27)
      - Version worked on by Diane Keaton and Jonathan Demme (Box 19, Folder 28)
    - Spawn of Evil
      - Character list; Scene list (Box 20, Folder 1)
      - Draft page 9; undated (Box 20, Folder 2)
        Typescript page
      - Preliminary treatment (Box 20, Folder 3)
      - Preliminary treatment (Box 20, Folder 4)
      - Preliminary treatment (Box 20, Folder 5)
      - Preliminary treatment (Box 20, Folder 6)
      - Typed letter Alan J. Pakula to McMurtry; Typed letter Arlene Friedman to McMurtry, December 17, 1964 (Box 20, Folder 7)
      - Draft, 1965 (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - The Stars Salute America's Greatest Films
      - Notes (Box 20, Folder 9)
      - Notepad with notes (Box 20, Folder 10)
      - Notes; Possible groupings (Box 20, Folder 11)
      - Preliminary draft; Note, October 7, 1977 (Box 20, Folder 12)
        Typescript draft, with corrections; Manuscript note
      - Memos from George Stevens, 1977 (Box 20, Folder 13)
      - Memo, Diana Elsas to George Stevens, October 13, 1977 (Box 20, Folder 14)
        Photocopied typed memos
      - Tribute to Citizen Kane by Francois Truffant (Box 20, Folder 15)
      - Notes on discussion between George Stevens, Jr. and Lauren Bacall; Page of draft of Bacall's speech, October 1977 (Box 20, Folder 16)
      - First draft with insertions (Box 20, Folder 17)
        Typescript (some photocopied)
      - First draft with insertions (Box 20, Folder 18)
      - Draft with insertions, November 9, 1977 (Box 20, Folder 19)
        Typescript (some photocopied), with notes
      - Draft with insertions, November 9, 1977 (Box 20, Folder 20)
      - Draft with insertions, November 9, 1977 (Box 20, Folder 21)
      - Draft, November 14, 1977 (Box 20, Folder 22)
      - Draft, undated (Box 20, Folder 23)
      - Draft pages, undated (Box 20, Folder 24)
      - Incomplete draft, undated (Box 20, Folder 25)
        Photocopied typescript draft, with corrections and notes
      - Intro Film Group F (Box 20, Folder 26)
      - Changes from Ron Clark (Box 20, Folder 27)
      - Changes from George Stevens (Box 20, Folder 28)
      - Short rundowns, November 1, 1977 (Box 20, Folder 29)
      - Short rundown, November 11, 1977 (Box 20, Folder 30)
      - Short rundown, November 15, 1977 (Box 20, Folder 31)
      - Short rundown, undated (Box 20, Folder 32)
      - Short rundown, undated (Box 20, Folder 33)
      - Blank rundown forms (Box 20, Folder 34)
      - Show material: AFI names; Outline; Distribution rights; Participants; Credits (Box 20, Folder 35)
        Typescripts; Photocopied publication pages
      - Staff list (Box 20, Folder 36)
      - Schedule; Slide and film order (Box 20, Folder 37)
    - Short Scripts
      - All American: Synopsis (Box 20, Folder 38)
      - Fear and Loathing in Las Vegas: First draft (Box 20, Folder 39)
      - Fear and Loathing in Las Vegas: First draft (Box 20, Folder 40)
      - Fear and Loathing in Las Vegas: Draft, March 1976 (Box 20, Folder 41)
      - Fear and Loathing in Las Vegas: Production version (Box 20, Folder 42)
      - The Rah Rah Route: Preliminary Step Sheet (Box 20, Folder 43)
      - The Rah Rah Route (Box 20, Folder 44)
      - The Streets of Laredo: first draft (Box 20, Folder 45)
      - Untitled script (Box 20, Folder 46)
    - American Film Essays
      - American Film Essays, October 1975-January 1977 (Box 20, Folder 47)
      - American Film Essays, February 1977- September 1977 (Box 20, Folder 48)
  - Other Writings
    - Short Prose and Poetry
      - In a Narrow Grave: Prospectus for a book of essays on Texas; Quotes from Dobie (Box 21, Folder 1)
      - In a Narrow Grave: The Cowboy's Lament - Outline; Chap. I-V, 1967 (Box 21, Folder 2)
      - In a Narrow Grave: The Cowboy's Lament - Chap. VI-IX, 1967 (Box 21, Folder 3)
      - In a Narrow Grave: The Cowboy's Lament - Chap. X-XI, 1967 (Box 21, Folder 4)
      - In a Narrow Grave: The Cowboy's Lament - Opening pages; Chap. I-III (Box 21, Folder 5)
        Typescript (carbon), with corrections
      - In a Narrow Grave: The Cowboy's Lament - Chap. IV-VII (Box 21, Folder 6)
      - In a Narrow Grave: The Cowboy's Lament - Chap. VIII-IX (Box 21, Folder 7)
      - In a Narrow Grave: The Cowboy's Lament - Essays on Texas (Box 21, Folder 8)
      - In a Narrow Grave: The Cowboy's Lament - Galley proof (Box 21, Folder 9)
      - In a Narrow Grave: Beat the Drum Slowly, Essays on Texas; Bibliography & Topic List (Box 21, Folder 10)
      - Bandit Goes to the Whorehouse (Box 21, Folder 11)
      - The Beat Academy in Janus (Box 21, Folder 12)
      - The Beginning of the Evening in Redneck Review, no. 1, Spring 1968 (Box 21, Folder 13)
      - Bederbecke in Avesta (Box 21, Folder 14)
      - Ben Jonson's Feud with the Poetasters, with bibliography and notes (Box 21, Folder 15)
      - The Best Day Since in Avesta (Box 21, Folder 16)
      - Coast to Coast, with mss note from Carol Edgar and envelope (Box 21, Folder 17)
        Photocopied galley proof, with notes
      - Credo, Watchfires, and Grandad's End in Coexistance Review, vol. 1, no. 2 (Box 21, Folder 18)
        Photocopies (2 copies)
      - Beauty, bear (Box 21, Folder 19)
      - Coexistance Review [vol. 1] with TLS, McMurtry to Mr. Brown (Box 21, Folder 20)
      - Coexistance Review, vol. 1, no. 2 (Box 21, Folder 21)
      - Cowboy, in Houston Post, May 26, 1963 (Box 21, Folder 22)
      - Cowboys and Cadillacs: Realism in the Movies in Riatta, Fall 1966 (Box 21, Folder 23)
      - Cowboys: Movies, Mythes and Cadillacs in Janus, with notes, Spring 1964 (Box 21, Folder 24)
        Full publication, with notes
      - Cowboys, Movies Myths and Cadillacs: Realism in the Western (Box 21, Folder 25)
      - Cowman (Box 21, Folder 26)
      - Dallas: A Reflection in Gentlemen's Magazine, March 1966 (Box 21, Folder 27)
        Typescript draft (carbon); Photocopy of clipping
      - Dunlop Crashes In in Playboy, July 1975 (Box 21, Folder 28)
      - Ever a Bridegroom: Reflections on Texas Literature; Second draft, unrevised (Box 21, Folder 29)
      - Ever a Bridegroom: Reflections on Texas Literature in The Texas Observer, October 23, 1981 (Box 21, Folder 30)
        Full publication; Photocopy of cover
      - Foreward for A Journey Through Texas by Frederick Law Olmstead (Box 21, Folder 31)
      - Horseman Pass By in The Rice Mill, vol. 1, no. 1, 1958 (Box 21, Folder 32)
      - Horseman Pass By in Southwest Review, 1961 (Box 21, Folder 33)
      - Tear sheets for Horseman Pass By in Southwest Review, Spring 1961 (Box 21, Folder 34)
      - Houston - Alphabetically Considered; First draft, Late 1965 (Box 21, Folder 35)
      - Houston: City in the Making: Second draft (Box 21, Folder 36)
        Typescript, with corrections; Photocopied typescript
      - Houston: City in the Making: Fourth draft (Box 21, Folder 37)
      - Hubris and the Pubis: A Shopper's Guide to the Sexual Revolution (Box 21, Folder 38)
      - Interview with Diane Keaton notes (Box 21, Folder 39)
      - Interview with Diane Keaton first draft, unused (Box 21, Folder 40)
      - Interview with Diane Keaton draft (Box 21, Folder 41)
      - Introduction to Tent Life in Siberia by George Kennan, revised (Box 21, Folder 42)
      - Introduction to Tent Life in Siberia by George Kennan: Draft, February 1986 (Box 21, Folder 43)
        Typescript draft, with corrections; Photocopy of same
      - Jessie and the Buyer (Box 21, Folder 44)
      - Journey to the End of the Road in Avesta (Box 21, Folder 45)
      - Hardbound journal with notes (Box 21, Folder 46)
      - Letter Grace David to Don Hendricks, with clipping of letter to the editor from LM, August 24, 1968 (Box 21, Folder 47)
      - Loneliness: An Essay, first draft and other draft: Typed letter Pattie Adcroft to McMurtry, October 3, 1983 (Box 21, Folder 48)
        Typescript draft, with corrections; Photocopied typescript; TLS
      - Love, Death, and the Astrodome: Early draft (Box 21, Folder 49)
      - Love, Death, and the Astrodome: Early draft (Box 21, Folder 50)
      - Love, Death, and the Astrodome: Early draft (Box 21, Folder 51)
      - Love, Death, and the Astrodome: Early draft (Box 21, Folder 52)
      - Love, Death, and the Astrodome: Final draft, with signature (Box 21, Folder 53)
        Typescript draft, with signature
      - Love, Death and the Astrodome in The Texas Observer, October 1, 1963 (Box 21, Folder 54)
        Full publication (3 copies)
      - Typed letter Miriam Kass to McMurtry; Typed letter McMurtry to Miriam Cass, May 15, 1967 (Box 21, Folder 55)
        TL; TLS
      - LSD: Why? interview by Miriam Kass in The Houston Post, May 28, 1967 (Box 21, Folder 56)
      - The Man Who Won the West in California Today, March 11, 1979 (Box 21, Folder 57)
      - Movie-Tripping: An Essay: Draft, signed by McMurtry (Box 21, Folder 58)
      - Movie-Tripping: My Own Rotten Film Festival in New York, vol. 6, no. 6, February 5, 1973 (Box 21, Folder 59)
        Clipping; Tearsheets
      - My Coast to Coast Compulsion, including notes (Box 21, Folder 60)
        Typescript draft, with notes
      - Notes on Vassar Miller in Janus (Box 22, Folder 1)
        Full publication (2 copies); Photocopy of clipping
      - The Old Soldier's Joy (Box 22, Folder 2)
      - The Old Soldier's Joy in Texas Quarterly (Box 22, Folder 3)
        Tearsheets
      - Our Revels Now are Ended: Chap I-II (Box 22, Folder 4)
      - A Primer of Postwar Fiction, outline and draft (Box 22, Folder 5)
      - The Questions a Writer Gets Asked: Two drafts (Box 22, Folder 6)
        Typescript drafts, with corrections
      - Retiring Undefeated: My Three Years Heading the Line at the Vassar Booksale: draft (Box 22, Folder 7)
      - Roll, Jordan, Roll in Avesta (Box 22, Folder 8)
        Full publication (2 copies)
      - Roll, Jordan, Roll in Avesta (Box 22, Folder 9)
        Photocopied tearsheets (2 copies, one missing one page)
      - Scribbling and Some of It's Consequences (Box 22, Folder 10)
        Typescript draft, with corrections, signed
      - Scribbling, Publishing, Writing (Box 22, Folder 11)
      - Spiegelgesichte (Box 22, Folder 12)
      - Take My Saddle From the Wall in Harpers (Box 22, Folder 13)
      - Texas from Stern to Stem first draft (Box 22, Folder 14)
      - Texas from Stern to Stem: second draft (Box 22, Folder 15)
      - Texas from Stern to Stem: third draft (Box 22, Folder 16)
        Typescript draft; Carbon of same
      - Texas from Stern to Stem: fourth draft; Typed letter Steven Wilkinson to McMurtry (Box 22, Folder 17)
        Typescript draft, with corrections; Carbon typescript; TLS
      - Texas from Stern to Stem: fifth draft (Box 22, Folder 18)
      - Texas: Good Times Gone, or Here Again in Holiday (Box 22, Folder 19)
      - Texas: Good Times Gone, or Here Again news article (Box 22, Folder 20)
      - Untitled Texas Monthly article, May (Box 22, Folder 21)
        Galley proofs, with notes
      - The Texas Moon, and Elsewhere: An Essay: first draft (incomplete) (Box 22, Folder 22)
      - The Texas Moon, and Elsewhere: An Essay: Typed letter Robert Manning to McMurtry (Box 22, Folder 23)
      - The Texas Moon, and Elsewhere: An Essay: first draft (Box 22, Folder 24)
      - The Texas Moon, and Elsewhere: An Essay: second draft (incomplete) (Box 22, Folder 25)
      - Proposed Thalia Stories: Notes in bluebook (Box 22, Folder 26)
      - Thalia Stories: There Will Be Peace in Korea (Box 22, Folder 27)
      - Thalia Stories III: The Everlasting Arms (Box 22, Folder 28)
      - Thalia Stories III: Breeding Carrell (Box 22, Folder 29)
      - The Trail Drives: Drafts and notes (Box 22, Folder 30)
        Typescript drafts (some photocopied), with corrections; Notes
      - Trending Back to Texas (Box 22, Folder 31)
      - Walter Benjamin at the Dairy Queen (Box 22, Folder 32)
      - Reliving My Days in High School, Freshman Engl. 101 theme, March 1959 (Box 22, Folder 33)
      - Poems: Evening Song; for John Lewis, divine; For Erwin Smith, Cowboy Photographer (Box 22, Folder 34)
        Typescript drafts; Tearsheets
      - Poem: Watch-Fires (Box 22, Folder 35)
      - Poem: The Watch-Fires (Box 22, Folder 36)
      - Poem: Yes, I am Old (Box 22, Folder 37)
      - Texas: Good Times Gone, or Here Again in Holiday, September 1965 (Box 27, Item 3)
    - Reviews
      - Review of In the American West by Richard Avedon: Notes (Box 22, Folder 38)
      - Review of In the American West by Richard Avedon: Drafts and galley proofs (Box 22, Folder 39)
        Photocopied typescript drafts, with corrections; Galley proofs
      - Review of Mountain Man by Vardis Fisher in Saturday Review, November 6, 1965 (Box 22, Folder 40)
        Full publication; Photocopy of clipping
      - Review of books by Frederick Law Olmstead and John Hull Olmstead (Box 22, Folder 41)
      - Review of The Accidental Tourist by Anne Tyler (Box 22, Folder 42)
      - Reviews for Chicago Tribune Book World, 1970s (Box 22, Folder 43)
      - Reviews for the Houston Post: misc. dates (Box 22, Folder 44)
      - Reviews for the New York Times, 1975 (Box 22, Folder 45)
      - Reviews for the Washington Star, 1976; undated (Box 22, Folder 46)
      - Reviews for The Washington Post, 1971 (Box 22, Folder 47)
      - Reviews for The Washington Post, 1972 (Box 22, Folder 48)
      - Reviews for The Washington Post, 1974 (Box 22, Folder 49)
      - Reviews for The Washington Post, 1974 (Box 22, Folder 50)
      - Reviews for The Washington Post, 1974 (Box 22, Folder 51)
      - Reviews for The Washington Post, 1975; 1979 (Box 22, Folder 52)
      - Reviews for The Washington Post, 1975 (Box 22, Folder 53)
      - Reviews for The Washington Post, 1975 (Box 22, Folder 54)
      - Reviews for The Washington Post, 1976 (Box 22, Folder 55)
      - Reviews for The Washington Post, 1976 (Box 22, Folder 56)
      - Reviews for The Washington Post, 1977 (Box 22, Folder 57)
      - Reviews for The Washington Post, 1977 (Box 22, Folder 58)
      - Reviews for The Washington Post, 1978 (Box 22, Folder 59)
    - Miscellaneous
      - Notes for speech honoring Henry Fonda (Box 22, Folder 60)
      - Notes on Dobie, Webb, Bedicheck, in Bluebooks (Box 22, Folder 61)
- Correspondence
  - Grace David
    - McMurtry to Grace David, July 20 (no year) (Box 22, Folder 62)
    - Postcard with signed note, Joe McMurtry to Grace David, July 22, 1965 (Box 22, Folder 63)
      Card with AS note
    - McMurtry to Grace David, September 17 (no year) (Box 22, Folder 64)
    - McMurtry to Grace David, [1967-1968] (Box 22, Folder 65)
      TLS, some with notes; Envelope
    - McMurtry to Grace David, [before 1971; 1971]; 1972; [before 1980] (Box 22, Folder 66)
      ALS; TLS; Envelope
    - McMurtry to Grace David, [1980-1985] (Box 22, Folder 67)
    - McMurtry to Grace David, [1986-1988] (Box 22, Folder 68)
    - McMurtry to Grace David, [1990-1994] (Box 22, Folder 69)
  - Mike Kunkel
    - McMurtry to Mike Kunkel; "The Untrodden Ways"; "Lonely Singer, Lonely Song", undated (Box 22, Folder 70)
      TL; Carbon typescript
    - McMurtry to Mike Kunkel, plus five stories, each with mss note from McMurtry (Box 22, Folder 71)
      ALS; Carbon typescripts; Mss notes
    - McMurtry to Mike Kunkel, 1955 (Box 22, Folder 72)
      ALS; TLS; envelopes
    - McMurtry to Mike Kunkel, January 7, 1956 (Box 22, Folder 73)
    - McMurtry to Mike Kunkel, August 12, 1956 (Box 22, Folder 74)
    - McMurtry to Mike Kunkel, 1957 (Box 22, Folder 75)
      TL; TLS; envelopes
  - John Leggett
    - John Leggett to McMurtry, 1960 (Box 22, Folder 76)
      TLS; Carbon of business papers
    - John Leggett to McMurtry, 1961 (Box 22, Folder 77)
    - John Howard Griffin to John Leggett, March 20, 1961 (Box 22, Folder 78)
    - Typed letter with note, A.B. Guthrie, Jr. to John Leggett, May 15, 1961 (Box 22, Folder 79)
      Photocopied TLS with mss note
    - John Leggett to Dirk Van Neuhuys, August 23, 1961 (Box 22, Folder 80)
    - John Leggett to Dorothea Oppenheimer, 1962-1963 (Box 22, Folder 81)
      Carbon TL
    - John Leggett to McMurtry, 1962 (Box 22, Folder 82)
    - John Leggett to McMurtry, 1963 (Box 22, Folder 83)
    - John Leggett to McMurtry, 1964-1965 (Box 22, Folder 84)
  - Others
    - Typed letter with note, McMurtry to Grover; Breeding Darrell, February 19 (no year) (Box 22, Folder 85)
      Photocopied TL, with note; Photocopied typescript
    - McMurtry to Miles Karpilow, [1963-1964] (Box 22, Folder 86)
      TLS; ALS
    - Steve Wilkinson to McMurtry; Material on Houston, May 18, 1905 (Box 22, Folder 87)
      TLS; Brochures
    - McMurtry to Marian Orgain, December 18, (1979?) (Box 22, Folder 88)
    - McMurtry to Mrs. D (Box 22, Folder 89)
    - McMurtry to Covington Rogers, 1980 (Box 22, Folder 90)
      TLS; Carbon TL
    - Covington Rogers to McMurtry and Joe M. Green, Jr., March 31, 1980 (Box 22, Folder 91)
    - Michael Evans to Bing Soph (Box 22, Folder 92)
    - McMurtry to "Dear Fellows"; Card with note, May 5, 1963 (Box 22, Folder 93)
      TLS; Notecard, with note
    - Mike Wise to McMurtry, March 12, 1984 (Box 22, Folder 94)
    - John Randolph Hall to McMurtry; Poems, [January 28, 1985] (Box 22, Folder 95)
      ALS; Photocopied typescript; Envelope
    - Mary C. Lethbridge to McMurtry, November 11, 1977 (Box 22, Folder 96)
      TLS; Envelope
    - Evan Thomas to McMurtry, March 15, 1960 (Box 22, Folder 97)
    - Rust Hills to McMurtry, July 6, 1960 (Box 22, Folder 98)
    - Stuart Harris to McMurtry, November 22, 1960 (Box 22, Folder 99)
    - McMurtry to Matthew Monahan, February 3, 1989 (Box 22, Folder 100)
    - McMurtry to James F. O'Roark, April 20, 1979 (Box 22, Folder 101)
    - McMurtry to "Dear Sirs" at Marlyn Books, two letters, June 22, no year; July 16, no year (Box 22, Folder 102)
- Other Projects
  This series contains documents related to other projects McMurtry was involved with. According to collection documentation, the items in the first series were projects which McMurtry said he was involved with in an uncredited role.
  - Scripts, Uncredited McMurtry Involvement
    - A Biography of God by Gregory Konakis (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Acts, story by Bob Rafelson and John Romano, screenplay by John Romano (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Emerald by Ronald Bass: Wire communication, Martin Starger to Jonathan Sanger, May 25, 1984 (Box 23, Folder 3)
      Photocopy
    - Emerald by Ronald Bass: Typed letter, Nancy Ambrose to McMurtry; Typescript pages, July 31, 1984 (Box 23, Folder 4)
      TL; Photocopied typescript pages
    - Emerald by Ronald Bass: Typed letter, Martin Starger to McMurtry; Typescript pages, August 22, 1984 (Box 23, Folder 5)
      TLS; Photocopied typescript pages
    - Emerald by Ronald Bass: Undated changes (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - Emerald by Ronald Bass: Undated draft (precedes June 1984 draft) (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - Emerald by Ronald Bass, April 18, 1984 (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - Emerald by Ronald Bass, June 1984 (Box 23, Folder 9)
      Typescript (some photocopied pages), with corrections and notes
    - Emerald by Ronald Bass, June 15, 1984 (Box 23, Folder 10)
      Photocopied typescript, with corrections and mss notes
    - Emerald by Ronald Bass, July 7, 1984 (Box 23, Folder 11)
      Photocopied typescript, with typed inserts that have notes
    - Ernie Kovacs' Zoomar, adaptation and screenplay by Robert Dolan Smith and W.F. Hale (Box 23, Folder 12)
    - Goin' South by John Harman Shaner and Al Ramrus, revised by Charles Shyer and Alan Mandel (Box 23, Folder 13)
    - Kingdom, story by Fred W. Miller, screenplay by William Martin and Horacce Newcomb: Draft, June 6, 1983 (Box 23, Folder 14)
    - Kingdom, story by Fred W. Miller, screenplay by William Martin and Horacce Newcomb.: Penultimate draft (corrected), November 22, 1983 (Box 23, Folder 15)
    - Last of the Red-Hot Poppas, a musical in two acts, book by Lanie Robertson, music and lyrics by Sid Selvidge (Box 23, Folder 16)
    - Little Miss Little Rock by Norris Church Mailer and B.C. Hall (Box 23, Folder 17)
    - Little Miss Little Rock by Norris Church Mailer and B.C. Hall. Second draft (Box 23, Folder 18)
    - Loveland: The Chronicle of an American Relationship, 1968-1978 by Barry Sandler (Box 23, Folder 19)
    - Mayflower Madam by Charles E. Israel (Box 23, Folder 20)
    - Missing Persons by Mark Kudlow and Lawrence Kaplan (Box 23, Folder 21)
    - Modern Bride by Nora Ephron and Alice Arlen (Box 23, Folder 22)
    - Mountains of the Moon by Bob Rafelson (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - My Stepmother is an Alien by Susan Rice, based on screenplays by Jerico Stone and Richard Benner (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Of Love and Dust, screenplay by Ernest J. Gaines, based on his novel (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Pretty Baby, screenplay by Polly Platt, story by Polly Platt and Louis Malle (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - Saint Jack by Paul Theroux and Peter Bogdanovich, based on the novel by Paul Theroux: First revised Draft, September 15, 1977 (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - Saint Jack by Paul Theroux and Peter Bogdanovich, based on the novel by Paul Theroux: Final Draft, September 29, 1977 (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - Searching a Fantasy by Carol Sobieski (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - The Golden Harp by Monty Diamond (Box 24, Folder 8)
    - The Kid by Ed Spielman: First draft, October 24, 1984 (Box 24, Folder 9)
    - The Kid by Ed Spielman: Second draft, May 3, 1985 (Box 24, Folder 10)
    - The Party by Fritz Roland (Box 24, Folder 11)
    - The Silver Spooner (novel) by Darcy O'Brian (Box 24, Folder 12)
    - The Silver Spooner by J.E. Dorsey, based on the novel by Darcy O'Brian: Draft, December 1, 1983 (Box 24, Folder 13)
    - The Women by Polly Platt (Box 24, Folder 14)
    - They All Laughed by Peter Bogdanovich (Box 24, Folder 15)
    - Truman, screenplay by Tom Topor (Box 24, Folder 16)
    - Wildflowers by Frank Cucci (Box 24, Folder 17)
  - Projects Considered
    - Los Angeles: Fabulous City by Victoria Wolff (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Lost Angeles: Fabulous City by Victoria Wolff (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Los Angeles: Photocopied TLS LM to Mr. Robson with general remarks and outline (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - Los Angeles: General Remarks (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - Los Angeles: Fabulous City, Outline, June 16, no year (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - Los Angeles: Fabulous City, Outline, June 25, 1975 (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - Los Angeles: Fabulous City, Background material (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - Cellmates by Arnold Hamilton; Typed letter Cyma Rubin to McMurtry; Interviews with Arnold Hamilton, July 1, 1982 (Box 25, Folder 8)
    - Cellmates by Arnold Hamilton (Box 25, Folder 9)
    - The Color Purple by Alice Walker: Novel with notes by McMurtry; Notes on Problems (Box 25, Folder 10)
    - Death on the Sixth Day by Henry Farrell: Copy of novel with notes by McMurtry (Box 25, Folder 11)
    - Hearts: Treatment; Typed letter McMurtry to Jane/Lois; Typed letter McMurtry to Jane/Lois, September 17, 1985; October 12, 1985 (Box 25, Folder 12)
    - Julie's Quest: First draft (Box 25, Folder 13)
    - Julie's Quest: Second draft (Box 25, Folder 14)
    - Julie's Quest: Unnumbered draft; Alternate ending (Box 25, Folder 15)
    - Julie's Quest: Unnumbered draft (Box 25, Folder 16)